So let's first talk about their first service
which would allow us to decouple our applications
which is Amazon SQS,
which stands for Simple Queue Service.
So what's a queue?
Well, say we are creating an SQS queue right here.
What we enable us to do is to have producers
send messages into that queue,
and then it could be one producer
but it could be as well, multiple producers.
And then once the messages are stored in the queue,
then they could be read by consumers
who will be polling the queue.
That means requesting messages from the queue.
They will be polling the queue
and it could be one consumer.
They could also be multiple consumers.
And in this example, once the consumer poll messages
they will share the work.
So each consumer will get different messages
and when they're done processing a message
maybe for example, to process a video
then they will delete the message
from the queue and it will be gone.
So in this mechanism, we have the producers sending messages
into the queue and they're decoupled from the consumer
reading the messages from the queue
and processing them at different speed.
So when you have an SQS
turns out that it is the AWS oldest offering.
It's over 10 years old.
It was one of the first services to appear
as part of the AWS cloud.
It is fully managed, so it's a serverless service.
You don't provision servers
and it's used to decouple applications.
So this is the exam tip.
If you see decouple, then think of SQS.
It will scale seamlessly from example, from one message
per second to tens of thousands of messages per second.
And the default retention
of the messages is four days, maximum of 14 days.
So you need to process them within that default retention.
There's no limit to how many messages can be in a queue.
And then once the consumers read the messages
then they have to be deleted.
So they're gone.
There is low latency, we're talking about less
than 10 milliseconds, unpublish and subscribe.
And then consumers share the work to read messages
and scale horizontally.
So SQS can be used to decouple
between your application tiers.
So here's a classic solution architecture.
We have our web servers and they're taking request
maybe through an application balancer.
They're served through EC2 instances
in an auto scaling group.
And then, for example, say that our users
want us to process some videos.
Then instead of sending it directly
to the video application, we can instead
insert messages into an SQS queue,
and then we will have a video processing layer
made of an auto scaling group with EC2 instances.
And these EC2 instances, we'll be reading from the SQS queue
and processing our videos.
The cool thing about it is that we can scale the second auto
scaling group independently from the first one
and this is why it's called decoupling.
And on top of it, the scaling can happen based
on how many messages, for example,
there are in the SQS queue.
And this would really allow us to have two layers,
the web servers and the video processing fully decoupled
from the SQS queue and scaling independently.
This will give us the best user experience
and also the best cost efficiency and scaling concerns.
Another feature for Amazon SQS is to have FIFO queues.
So FIFO means First In First Out, and that corresponds
to the ordering of the messages within the queue.
So if you have a producer sending messages
in a specific order such as 1, 2, 3, and 4
then the consumer will also read these messages in order.
So example 1, 2, 3, 4.
So when you have a normal SQS queue
consumers can read messages altogether
and they could be in different orders.
But with Amazon SQS FIFO queues
the message are going to be in order
and it's just a feature you need to remember for the exam.
Okay, that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.